PRASAD KULKARNI

Flat 103, Bastekiya bldg.., Near musalla Roundabout, Bur Dubai Cell (+971) 56 276 6137,(+91)90 28 96 60 77, pkulkarni700@gmail.com · Linkedin.com/in/prasad7k/

To obtain a challenging role as a Professional Structural BIM Modeler/Coordinator with my 15 years of industry experience. Seeking an opportunity to utilize my skills in Revit Structure, MWF, and Bluebeam. Focused on accuracy, quality producing Revit models and detailed drawings. Strong background in Revit modeling, detailing and proven track record of delivering quality work. I am confident that I can make valuable contributions to any project team.

Professional Work Experience

AUG 2021 - MAR 2023

FREELANCE MODELER, CLIENT FTF-USA

As a freelancer, my responsibilities include creating BIM models and various building types using Revit and MWF, utilizing BIM360 design. Generating shop drawings for actual construction documents and machine files.

JAN 2020 - JUN 2021

EXCEUTIVE MODELER. KATERRA-PUNE-INDIA

- Created structural BIM models and construction documents for a variety of building types using Revit, MWF software.
- Created model views, building plans and layouts, sketches, and construction details.
- Coordinated with structural engineers to gather building design, layout, structural details.
- Design and troubleshoot standardized steel framing conditions with project specific requests.
- Generated and Verify fabrication drawings, Bill of Materials, and reports.
- Understanding of load-bearing framing (in Metal and Wood).
- Use of BIM360 design to optimize modeling across offices and act as gatekeeper for incoming/outgoing models/documentation.
- Interested in new BIM technologies and Automation processes.

DEC 2018 - JUN 2019

BIM MODELER/COORDINATOR, MEINHARDT-DOHA-QATAR

- Created structural BIM models and construction documents for a variety of building types using Revit, including commercial construction.
- Created model views, building plans and layouts, sketches, and construction details.
- Coordinated with structural engineers to gather building dimensions, drawing requirements, structural details and drawing markups.
- Developed Schedule for Structural Columns, Framing, Foundations and Legends.
- Export CAD and PDF drawings as per client requirement.
- Annotated Sections and Details project up to (LOD-300).

JAN 2018 - DEC 2018

REVIT OPEATOR, AEB-DOHA-QATAR

- BIM execution of Qatar Rails projects from various inputs from design development (DD) stage.
- Prepared Structural design model views and drawings as per BIM Guidelines.
- Creation of Structural design details in REVIT according to standards.
- Created Accurate LOD 350 Structural Model and Detailing drawings.
- Established and executed BIM project workflow for ensuring quality.
- Revit model split and up-gradation according to BIM needs. Also, linking different discipline Revit models and clash resolve.
- Collaborated with project manager and field leads.

MAY 2014 - DEC 2017

STRUCTURAL REVIT MODELER, ADS-PUNE-INDIA

- Experienced projects up to LOD-400 (Tekla).
- Prepared BIM Models and drawings of buildings, Concrete Structures, Steel Structures frames.
- Developed engineer's concept into accurate models and drawings through direct comminutions.
- Carry out shop drawing reviews against contract documents.
- Coordinated framing model and drawing with adjacent scope leads.
- Developed library of prefabrications details and model.
- Adhere to BIM execution plan and BIM project workflow criteria.
- Created Structural Schematic Design Model.
- Developed 3D model as per Gravity Design and Lateral Design information.
- Created Schedules and connection details.

FEB 2011 - FEB 2014

DESIGNER. NEILSOFT-PUNE-INDIA

- Check precast layout drawings and fabrication drawings for accuracy and construct ability.
- Check quantities and bill of materials.
- Coordinated with the design team and precast plant personnel.
- Created structural detailed shop drawings for Precast Columns, Girders, Spandrel, Wall panel.
- Created details of erections, elevation, and sketches etc.,
- Experienced in preparation of Structural concept, Detailed Design, IFC drawings.
- Calculating quantity of steels for reinforced concrete and bar bending schedule.
- Adhering to codes and standards, preparation of drawings reports as per project requirements in compliance with company standards.
- Knowledge of originating the drawing as per customer standards.
- Developed as Build drawing at end of project and submitted final soft copy to client.

JUN 2007 - JAN 2011

JR. DETAILER, J+W CONSULANT-PUNE-INDIA

- Created Columns, Footing, Beams, Slab, Foundation drawings
- Prepared Structural working drawings as per Engineer's Guidelines
- Prepared RCC drawing for Boiler area foundation, Powerhouse Foundations, Canteen Building.
- Prepared RCC drawing DG house, Pipe Racks, Foundations
- Structural Steel works included Roof truss, Top and Bottom Chord, columns, floor framing and bracing
- Prepared drawings of foundation layout.
- Created Framing plans and developed reinforcement schedules.
- Developed Column, Beams, Slab reinforcement schedule.
- Prepared RCC Typical details. Foundation details, Retaining wall details, Beam details, Column details.
- Developed RCC plan, sections, and elevations.

EDUCATION

APRIL 2005

MASTER OF ARTS, SHIVAJI UNIVERSITY KOLHAPUR

Specialization in Marathi

MARCH 2003

BACHELOR OF ARTS, SHIVAJI UNIVERSITY KOLHAPUR

Specialization in Political Science, Economics, Sociology

> SKILLS

- Analytical thinking
- Planning in attention to details research
- Communication skill (written & verbal)

- Hardworking
- Willingness to learn new things.
- Troubleshooting towards problem

CERTIFICATES

- AutoCAD 2009
- Spoken English B1 Level

Autodesk Revit Struture-2012

Declaration:

I hereby affirm that the information provided in this document is accurate and true to the best of my knowledge.